<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on koolaidxk1d</title>
    <link>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on koolaidxk1d</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:38:23 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Infographics</title>
      <link>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/infographics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:38:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/infographics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OverTheWire: Natas</title>
      <link>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/natas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 18:16:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/natas/</guid>
      <description>Back for more password hunting! This time we are doing a more web-oriented wargame. Similarly to leviathan, no hints are given on the webpage. This game provides no SSH access; everything is done in the browser.
I&amp;rsquo;m lacking in web-dev knowledge to say the least, so this will be quite challenging.
Level 0 The password is right in your face the moment you look at the html.
Level 1 Same story as level 0, however the workaround is just using the hotkey to open the inspector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Links</title>
      <link>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 18:16:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/links/</guid>
      <description>Services evoxt.com - cheap VPS, good customer support
real-debrid.com - very cheap, unlocks all paid filehost websites (1fichier etc.). Also converts torrents to direct http downloads. A must-have for movie obtainers.
Web Tools deepl/translator - better than google translate
Photopea - photoshop clone, free, no signup
excalidraw - like ms paint, free, no signup
dogbolt.org - Online decompiler
CyberChef/ - Extremely useful all-in-one hacking web tool
justbeamit or WeTransfer- P2P direct file transfer, drag n drop, no sign up</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 19:30:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>Y2K zoomer interested in offensive security. No professional experience &amp;hellip; yet.
The purpose of my blog is to learn in public. Hopefully by writing these posts I can not only help myself but possibly help others who stumble upon them.
Thanks This blog is written with Obsidian, compiled with Hugo, and hosted with Github pages.
The Hugo theme in use is Diary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OverTheWire: Leviathan</title>
      <link>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/leviathan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 12:36:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://koolaidxk1d.github.io/posts/leviathan/</guid>
      <description>OverTheWire&amp;rsquo;s Leviathan wargame is all about reverse engineering of x86 binaries. The description of the game states that it only requires knowledge of linux command line utilities, and little to no programming experience.
Each level goes as such:
You ssh into the server as the user whose password you obtained from the previous level. Through whatever means necessary, you get the password to the next level. There are no hints given for any of the levels, so it is completely up to us to figure out what we are looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
